

### Profile

Hi there, I'm Ilia Android Engineer with 10 years of experience. I have more than 20+ successfully completed projects, participation in open source, tech writer(habr/medium) and QnA participant.

Deep knowledge of android architecture, design patterns, mobile CI/CD. Specialize in product development. Interested in business, finance, psychology, and tech reading; extreme mobile architecture and trend(pop) mobile technologies.

# Employment History

Android Engineer at Humans Group, Minsk / Warsaw

January 2020 — Present

Humans.uz is a telecom-banking-marketplace platform in Uzbekistan.

Technical and resource management. Increasing feature delivery speed: setup decomposition and development process between features (usually 2-4 persons by 1 feature); decrease build time - split technical parts of the application by modules and pack it to the binary storage. As a result increase feature delivery time from 2 months to 3 weeks.

#### Android Engineer at Yandex, Minsk

June 2018 — June 2019

Yandex Browser. Chromium fork for android mobile application.

Development GUI features, work by quotes: bugfix, feature and automation QA.

Improve team adaptation process with the transformation from Java to Kotlin as a main project language by formalization and integration kotlin lint rules.

### Other work experience:

- HiQo Solutions, Inc.(Android Engineer); Jun 2019 Jan 2020
- Yellow(Android Engineer); Jun 2015 Jun 2018
- ITM House(Middle Android Developer); Oct 2014 Jun 2015
- Vega Systems(Middle Android Developer); Feb 2014 Sep 2014
- Medical Software Solutions (Junior Android Developer); Nov 2012
  Feb 2014

## Education

Bachelor, BSUIR, Minsk

September 2009 — July 2014

BSUIR, Faculty of computer systems and networks

# Details

Warsaw

Poland

pavlovskii\_ilya@mail.ru

Date of birth

08.03.1992

Nationality

Belarusian

#### Links

linkedin github

## **Skills**

Kotlin, Java

GraphQL, REST

GIT, Gradle, Android SDK, Coroutines, KMM

Ruby, Python, C/C++, Bash

### Languages

Russian

English

Polish

# ➤ Extra-curricular activities

## Stickerbox at Skywind Hackaton., Minsk

August 2016 — August 2016

"Stickerbox" - entertainment application to make custom sticker and send them via android keyboard.

Diplomas: "Completed MVP"; "Drive and fun app"; "Selection of the jury"

## Geography School education app at Engineering Jam 3, Minsk

August 2019 — August 2019

Geography School education app to solve geography quizzes. Participation, no prize

## Courses

**CCNA Exploration: Network Fundamentals** 

August 2013

**CCNA Exploration: Routing Protocols and Concept** 

August 2013

E-legion & Google. Android Developer school

June 2015